Guide to the Stanford News Service Audiovisual Recordings SC1125
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Videorecordings, 1936-2011; Series 2
  - Kennell Jackson Memorial Service, 01/17/2006; 06-0117-3b; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 26)
  - Kennell Jackson Memorial Service, 01/17/2006; 06-0117-3c; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 26)
  - Kennell Jackson Memorial Service, 01/17/2006; 06-0117-3d; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 26)
  - Aurora Forum: Celebrating South African Freedom, 01/21/2006; 06-0121-1a; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 26)
    Aurora Forum: Celebrating South African Freedom: A Symposium on the International Campaign to End Apartheid The forum included the debut of an episode of the documentary "Have You Heard From Johannesburg", produced and directed by Connie Field. Speakers: Clayborne Carson, professor of history; Connie Field, documentary filmmaker; Amanda Kemp, Stanford alum active in anti-apartheid efforts; Donald Kennedy, Stanford president emeritus; Steve Phillips, Stanford alum active in anti-apartheid effort; Justice Albie Sachs, member of the South African Constitutional Court
  - Aurora Forum: Celebrating South African Freedom, 01/21/2006; 06-0121-1c; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 26)
  - Cornel West, Princeton professor of religion, "Equity Matters" forum, Dinkelspiel, 01/28/2006; 06-0128-1a; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    Cornel West, professor of religion at Princeton, "Equity Matters: Creating Educational Opportunities for All Students," forum and discussion in Dinkelspiel Auditorium, 10th anniversary meeting of the Foundation for a College Education, sponsored by the School of Education and the Foundation for a College Education in East Palo Alto. N6 (NG?) to 19:00
  - Cornel West, Princeton professor of religion, "Equity Matters" forum, Dinkelspiel, 01/28/2006; 06-0128-1b; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    Cornel West, professor of religion at Princeton, "Equity Matters: Creating Educational Opportunities for All Students," forum and discussion in Dinkelspiel Auditorium, 10th anniversary meeting of the Foundation for a College Education, sponsored by the School of Education and the Foundation for a College Education in East Palo Alto.
  - Clayborne Carson on life of Coretta Scott King (d. 1/31/2006). Field tape, 01/31/2006; 06-0131-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    History Professor Clayborne Carson, founder and director of the Martin Luther King, Jr., Research & Education Institute on the life of Coretta Scott King (died 1/31/2006). Field tape
  - American ABC: Childhood in 19th-Century America, Cantor Arts Center exhibition, 02/01/2006; 06-0201-1a; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    American ABC: Childhood in 19th-Century America, exhibition at the Cantor Arts Center (catalog has title, Young America: Childhood in 19th-Century Art and Culture). HD
  - American ABC: Childhood in 19th-Century America, Cantor Arts Center exhibition, 02/01/2006; 06-0201-1b; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
  - Dr. Norman Shumway Tribute Press Conference, 02/10/2006; 06-0210-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    Press Conference in tribute to Norman Edward Shumway, Jr., the Frances and Charles D. Field Professor of Cardiothoracic Surgery, Emeritus. He was born on February 9, 1923 and died on February 10, 2006.
  - Dr. Norman Shumway Tribute Press Conference, 02/10/2006; 06-0210-2; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 26)
    Press Conference in tribute to Norman Edward Shumway, Jr., the Frances and Charles D. Field Professor of Cardiothoracic Surgery, Emeritus. He was born on February 9, 1923 and died on February 10, 2006. (standard dub of hi-def 06-0120-1)
  - Umran Inan, space weather gamma-ray flare disturbs ionosphere, 02/21/2006; 06-0221-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    Electrical engineering Professor Umran Inan discusses a rare gamma-ray flare from a distant star and how it disturbed the Earth's daytime ionosphere in conjunction with the American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS) annual meeting.
  - Math consulting professor Keith Devlin "What Do Mathematicians (Usually) Mean by Proof?, 02/21/2006; 06-0221-2; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    Mathematics consulting professor Keith Devlin talk "What Do Mathematicians (Usually) Mean by Proof?" during symposium, "Paradise Lost? The Changing Nature of Mathematical Proof" in conjunction with the American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS) annual meeting.
  - Parents Weekend 2006, 02/24/2006; 06-0224-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    Students were visited by family members Feb. 24-25 during Parents' Weekend.
  - Stanley and Solstice cars honored by city of Palo Alto, 02/28/2006; 06-0228-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    City of Palo Alto honors Stanford Solar Car Project (vehicle named Solstice) and Stanford Racing Team (vehicle Stanley) and the School of Engineering students behind the vehicles for their inventiveness and technical contributions.
  - Lucy Shapiro Avian Flu, 03/02/2006; 06-0302-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 26)
    Developmental Biology professor Lucy Shapiro on the potential spread of avian flu
  - Kapur and Bunn discuss U.S. - India nuclear agreement (CISAC), 03/09/2006; 06-0309-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 26)
    Two experts on nuclear issues, Paul Kapur and George Bunn, of the Freeman-Spogli Institute for International Studies at Stanford, outline some of the arguments surrounding the nuclear agreement signed last week in New Delhi by the United States and India. The agreement is not part of the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty (NPT), which India has not signed. unclear what day this event happened, it went up on SRO on march 9th 2006
  - Dish Demolition Full tape, 03/10/2006; 06-0310-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    Dish Demolition
  - George Lucas (Lucasfilm) receiving American Academy of Arts and Sciences Founders Award, SF Backup 1, 03/18/2006; 06-0318-1a; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 26)
    George Lucas (Lucasfilm) receiving American Academy of Arts and Sciences Founders Award at the Letterman Digital Arts Center, San Francisco Presidio
  - George Lucas (Lucasfilm) receiving American Academy of Arts and Sciences Founders Award, SF Backup 2, 03/18/2006; 06-0318-1b; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 26)
  - Computer Science at 40 Session 4, Upstarts & Rabble Rousers 80 min, 03/21/2006; 06-0321-1a; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 26)
    01:20:00
    40 Years of Computer Science At Stanford, A Symposium & Celebration, Session 4, Startup Panel, Upstarts & Rabble Rousers. Panel (from website) John Markoff (Moderator), Adjunct Faculty, Stanford Dept. of Communication, & Senior Writer for The New York Times & Business Day; Andy Bechtolsheim, Chief Architect and Senior Vice President, Network Systems, Sun Microsystems; James H Clark, Founder of Silicon Graphics, Netscape, Healtheon, & MyCFO; David Filo, Co-Founder and Chief Yahoo, Yahoo! Inc.; Mark Horowitz, Professor of Electrical Engineering and of Computer Science, Stanford; Mendel Rosenblum, Associate Professor of Computer Science and, by courtesy, of Electrical Engineering, Stanford University, Co-Founder & Chief Scientist of VMware, Inc.; David Shaw, Founder & Chairman of D.E. Shaw, Inc.; Jerry Yang, Co-Founder and Chief Yahoo, Yahoo! Inc.
  - Computer Science at 40 Session 4, Upstarts & Rabble Rousers 60 min, 03/21/2006; 06-0321-1b; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 26)
  - Bloomberg B-roll TRT 2:30, 03/23/2006; 06-0323-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 26)
    00:02:30
  - Move of Mariposa and Serra Houses for Munger, Interview, Susan Rozakis, 03/27/2006; 06-0327-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    To make room for the Munger Graduate Residences, a 600-bed dormitory complex planned for construction near the Law School, Rogers, Mariposa and Serra houses were hoisted onto the back of giant trailers and hauled to their new location next to the Bechtel International Center. Includes interview with Susan Rozakis, Stanford Department of Project Management
  - 1906 Press conference, USGS, Menlo Park, Beroza, Zoback, Poland, Aagaard, 03/28/2006; 06-0328-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    1906 Press conference, USGS, Menlo Park: Greg Beroza (Stanford Geophysics); Mary Lou Zoback (USGS), Chris Poland (CEO Degenkolb Associates and chairman of the 100th Anniversary Earthquake Conference); Brad Aagaard (USGS) Scientists Recreate Ground Shaking from the 1906 Earthquake and Discuss What's in Store for the Earthquake Conference April 18-22, 2006
  - Munger Moving Day #2 Houses, 03/30/2006; 06-0330-1a; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    To make room for the Munger Graduate Residences, a 600-bed dormitory complex planned for construction near the Law School, Rogers, Mariposa and Serra houses were hoisted onto the back of giant trailers and hauled to their new location next to the Bechtel International Center.
  - Munger Moving Day #2 Houses, 03/30/2006; 06-0330-1b; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
  - Quake Drill Press Conference, 04/06/2006; 06-0406-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    Earthquake drill Press Conference, Faculty Club. Regina Phelps, consultant with EMS Solutions; John Etchemendy, Stanford Provost
  - Geophysics prof Greg Beroza presents new animation on 1906 SF earthquake, 04/10/2006; 06-0410-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    The Great San Francisco Earthquake of April 18, 1906, was a watershed in the history of earthquake science, says Stanford geophysics Professor Gregory Beroza. In this video, Beroza presents new animation based, in part, on his recent study suggesting that the 1906 quake was much bigger than earlier estimates. Includes animation produced by the U.S. Geological Survey
  - Hennessy Arts speech to Academic Council, 04/20/2006; 06-0420-1a; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    President John Hennessy annual speech to the Academic Council, "A Cultured and Useful Citizenry: The Role of Creativity and the Arts in a 21st-Century Education.
  - Hennessy Arts speech to Academic Council, 04/20/2006; 06-0420-1b; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
  - Take Our Daughters and Sons to Work Day--News Service program, 04/27/2006; 06-0427-1a; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 26)
    Nine boys and girls visited the News Service on April 27, 2006, to participate in the annual campus-wide Take Our Daughters and Sons to Work Day. After receiving a crash course in Journalism 101 from the News Service staff, the young reporters--whose ages ranged from 9 to 12--conducted one-on-one interviews with each other and with news director Elaine Ray. As the video shows, the future journalists managed to write, illustrate and produce a special edition of Stanford Report in just two hours.
  - Take Our Daughters and Sons to Work Day--News Service program, 04/27/2006; 06-0427-1b; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 26)
  - Bob Bowlsby New Athletic Director, 04/28/2006; 06-0428-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    Bob Bowlsby (University of Iowa Director of Athletics) selected as Stanford's next athletic director
  - Dean Wilkening's anthrax study for CISAC, 05/09/2006; 06-0509-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    Dean WIlkening, director of the science program at Stanford's Center for International Security and Cooperation (CISAC), talks about his study of a 1979 accidental release of anthrax in the former Soviet Union and his new models of medical effects of inhalational anthrax.
  - SF Bay Delta levee system potential breach press conference, 05/10/2006; 06-0510-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    A magnitude 6.5 earthquake could severely damage the San Francisco Bay Delta levee system and cut off vital water supplies for millions of Californians, according to experts at a May 10 press conference at Stanford's Blume Earthquake Engineering Center. Martin McCann, consulting professor of civil and environmental engineering, and retired Brig. Gen. Gerald Galloway of the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers discussed their concerns about the integrity of U.S. levees in the wake of Hurricane Katrina.
  - Simulated SF Bay Delta Levee Breach Animation, 05/10/2006; 06-0510-2; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 26)
    00:00:35
    A magnitude 6.5 earthquake could severely damage the San Francisco Bay Delta levee system and cut off vital water supplies for millions of Californians, according to experts at a May 10 press conference at Stanford's Blume Earthquake Engineering Center.
  - Iraqi students meet with Hennessy NOT FOR AIR, 05/19/2006; 06-0519-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    Iraqi students meet with President Hennessy. NOT FOR AIR
  - Community Service Awards, 05/19/2006; 06-0519-2a; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    The Foundation for a College Education, Planting for the Second Hundred Years and Ravenswood Family Health Center were honored May 19 with Stanford Community Partnership Awards. Donald Barr, an associate professor (teaching) of sociology and human biology, and law Professor Michael Wald also were presented with the Miriam Aaron Roland Volunteer Service Prize during the luncheon, which was held at the Garden Court Hotel in Palo Alto.
  - Community Service Awards, 05/19/2006; 06-0519-2b; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
  - Jesse Cool Carrots 'N Cantor Arts Center, 2006; 06-0526-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    Jesse Cool runs the Cool Café at the Cantor Center for Visual Arts and a garden of edible plants on Stanford property.
  - Jesse Cool Interview, 06/02/2006; 06-0602-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    Interview with Jesse Cool who runs the Cool Café at the Cantor Center for Visual Arts and a garden of edible plants on Stanford property.
  - Graduate student commencement address, Vartan Gregorian, 06/17/2006; 06-0617-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    Vartan Gregorian (AB 1958; PhD 1964 History) since 1997 the president of the Carnegie Corporation, delivered the 2006 graduate student commencement address at Elliott Field, Saturday, June 17. The university held separate Commencement exercises this year for students earning advanced degrees and those receiving undergraduate degrees, due to construction at Stanford Stadium.
  - Graduate student commencement, Vartan Gregorian. Cutaway shots, 06/17/2006; 06-0617-2; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
  - Graduate student commencement, Program record, Standard definition, 06/17/2006; 06-0617-3a; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 26)
  - Graduate student commencement, Program record, Standard definition, 06/17/2006; 06-0617-3b; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 26)
  - Undergraduate commencement address, Tom Brokaw, part 1, TRT 53:00, 06/18/2006; 06-0618-1a; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 26)
    00:53:00
    115th Commencement culminated Sunday with the ceremony to award undergraduate degrees to more than 1,700 students at Elliott Field. The keynote speaker was broadcast-news icon and author Tom Brokaw. The university held separate Commencement exercises this year for students earning advanced degrees and those receiving undergraduate degrees, due to construction at Stanford Stadium.
  - Undergraduate commencement address, Tom Brokaw, part 2, TRT 59:00, 06/18/2006; 06-0618-1b; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 26)
  - Undergraduate commencement, Wacky Walk, Cutaway shots HC-1, 06/18/2006; 06-0618-2a; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
  - Undergraduate commencement, Wacky Walk, Cutaway shots, 06/18/2006; 06-0618-2b; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    Tom Brokaw at 23:45-44:00 [maybe; needs to be watched] 115th Commencement culminated Sunday with the ceremony to award undergraduate degrees to more than 1,700 students at Elliott Field. The keynote speaker was broadcast-news icon and author Tom Brokaw. The university held separate Commencement exercises this year for students earning advanced degrees and those receiving undergraduate degrees, due to construction at Stanford Stadium.
  - Undergraduate commencement address, Tom Brokaw, podium, HC-1, 06/18/2006; 06-0618-3a; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
  - Undergraduate commencement address, Tom Brokaw, podium, 06/18/2006; 06-0618-3b; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
  - CEES Launch, John Hennessy, Scott McNealy, Jerry Harris, 06/20/2006; 06-0620-1a; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    Center for Computational Earth and Environmental Science (CEES) officially launched June 20 at Mitchell Earth Sciences Building. Stanford alumnus Scott McNealy, chairman of the board of directors of Sun Microsystems Inc., joined geophysics professor and CEES director Jerry Harris, and president John Hennessy.
  - CEES Launch, John Hennessy, Scott McNealy, Margot Gerritsen demo, 06/20/2006; 06-0620-1b; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    Center for Computational Earth and Environmental Science (CEES) officially launched June 20 at Mitchell Earth Sciences Building. Stanford alumnus Scott McNealy, chairman of the board of directors of Sun Microsystems Inc., joined geophysics professor and CEES director Jerry Harris, and president John Hennessy. This tape includes demonstration by assistant professor of energy resources engineering Margot Gerritsen.
  - Krishna Shenoy, Interview, Prosthetic device for Paralyzed, 07/06/2006; 06-0706-1a; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    Krishna Shenoy, PhD, assistant professor of electrical engineering and of neuroscience, and his team are working on a brain-computer interface for use in guiding prosthetic devices for the paralyzed.
  - Krishna Shenoy Prosthetic device for Paralyzed, 07/06/2006; 06-0706-1b; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
  - Paralyze Master Prosthetics engineering TRT 6:09 (or 6:45), 07/13/2006; 06-0713-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 26)
    00:06:45
    Krishna Shenoy, PhD, assistant professor of electrical engineering and of neuroscience, and his team are working on a brain-computer interface for use in guiding prosthetic devices for the paralyzed. Total run time is both labeled as 6:09 (or 6:45).
  - Elephant Research Project, Etosha National Park, Namibia, July 2004, 07/20/2006; 06-0720-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 26)
    Stanford biologist Caitlin O'Connell-Rodwell and her colleagues conducted an elaborate elephant communication experiment in Namibia's Etosha National Park in July 2004. Their findings suggest that elephants produce powerful, low frequency vocalizations that travel through the ground. These seismic signals might be used to find distant mates or identify potential predators. In this video, Caitlin and husband Tim Rodwell demonstrate how wild elephants react when acoustic recordings are converted into seismic vibrations—a daytime experiment in which the sounds of frightened elephants are played back underground, and a nighttime test using a synthesized warble tone.
  - Stadium Rollout Footage, 08/22/2006; 06-0822-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    Stanford Stadium footage prior to renovation.
  - Hot/Cold Football Practice Stanford, 09/05/2006; 06-0905-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
  - 116th Convocation, 9/19/2006; 06-0919-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    John Hennessy delivered the keynote address at the university's 116th Opening Convocation held Sept. 19 in the Main Quad
  - Frosh arrive at Branner Hall; John Hennessy, 09/19/2006; 06-0919-2; 1 videotape(s) (Box 26)
    Freshmen arrive at Branner Hall during New Student Orientation; John Hennessy delivered the keynote address at the university's 116th Opening Convocation held Sept. 19 in the Main Quad
  - USS Macon press conference, MBARI / NOAA / MBNMS, Moss Landing; Steve Rock, 09/27/2006; 06-0927-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    USS Macon wreckage surveyed on the floor of Monterey Bay; press conference held at Moss Landing, California with Monterey Bay Aquarium Research Institute (MBARI), Monterey Bay National Marine Sanctuary, National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA)'s Office of Exploration; Interview with Stephen Rock, professor of aeronautics and astronautics.
  - USS Macon Expedition Media Roll, NOAA / MBARI (PR-144), 09/27/2006; 06-0927-2; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 26)
    USS Macon wreckage surveyed on the floor of Monterey Bay; Monterey Bay Aquarium Research Institute (MBARI), National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA)'s Office of Exploration supplied media roll. Cabinet drawer space includes shot list for the video. This is not a News Service-produced video
  - Nobel Prize Roger Kornberg press conference, 10/04/2006; 06-1004-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    Roger Kornberg, professor of structural biology, won the 2006 Nobel Prize in Chemistry
  - Nobel Prize Roger Kornberg champagne reception, 10/05/2006; 06-1005-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
  - Deborah Stipek Interview, 10/06/2006; 06-1006-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    Deborah Stipek, dean of the School of Education in an interview with Stanford News Service reporter Lisa Trei. Stipek outlines the objectives of Stanford's new K-12 Initiative and why high quality teacher education is essential to training good teachers
  - Talal Asad lecture "Thinking About Blasphemy and Secular Criticism", 10/09/2006; 06-1009-1a; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    "Thinking About Blasphemy and Secular Criticism" Presidential Lecture presented by Talal Asad, the Distinguished Professor of Anthropology at the City University of New York (CUNY) Graduate Center. At Cubberley Auditorium, School of Education
  - Talal Asad lecture "Thinking About Blasphemy and Secular Criticism", 10/09/2006; 06-1009-1b; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
  - Christiane Amanpour (1st Daniel Pearl Memorial Lecture), 10/17/2006; 06-1017-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    Christiane Amanpour, chief international correspondent for CNN, delivered the first annual Daniel Pearl Memorial Lecture on Oct. 17 in Kresge Auditorium. In her talk, "Journalism and the World," Amanpour reflected on the media coverage of international issues since 9/11 and the Bush administration's failures in Iraq. The lecture series has been established in memory of Daniel Pearl, who graduated from Stanford in 1985 with a bachelor's degree in communication, and was kidnapped and killed in Pakistan in 2002 while researching a story on Islamic militants for the Wall Street Journal.
  - Nobel Winners (9) Montage, 10/27/2006; 06-1027-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 26)
    00:02:16
    Roger Kornberg, professor of structural biology, won 2006 Nobel prize in chemistry; Andrew Fire, professor of pathology and of genetics, awarded the 2006 Nobel Prize in physiology or medicine
  - Stanford Faculty Club: Chuck Perry, General Manager, I-view & tour, 10/27/2006; 06-1027-2; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    Bang-for-the-buck buffet, good lodging, a new elevator and an upgraded library are the hallmarks of the newly improved Stanford Faculty Club (on Lagunita Drive next to Tresidder Union). General Manager Chuck Perry conducts a tour.
  - Keith Devlin on New Math 15 Course, 10/31/2006; 06-1031-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)
    Math is all around us, says Keith Devlin, consulting professor. Devlin is teaching Math 15 this winter for the "math-averse." Underscoring lessons about how math drives cell phone technology, video games, DSL, and Google, Math 15 will require some hard work; the results will be new skills and understanding of the numbers game.
  - StickyBot, SpinyBot in Mechanical Engineering. Field tape, November 2006, 11/00/2006; 06-1100-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 26)
    StickyBot and SpinyBot are Robots in Scansorial Environments (RISE) projects at the Stanford Biomimetics and Dexterous Manipulation Lab.
  - Andrew Ng, Robot, dishwasher, 11/02/2006; 06-1102-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV-HDV) (Box 26)